Contact

862-324-5300 (Mobile) lkosnik@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/linda-kosnik-31b1b214 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare Management Hospitals Human Resources

Certifications

Wharton/Johnson and Johnson Fellow, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

Honors-Awards

NJ Governor's Award for Quality

Linda Kosnik

Vice President Patient Care Services/CNO

Baltimore, Maryland Area

Summary

Board and C-suite Advisor • Operations & Clinical Leader • Value Creator • Innovative Solutions Leader

Senior executive with leadership experience in large-scale organizations, I am a healthcare operations expert proven in driving positive change.

My background spans various roles executing CNO, COO and SVP roles against aggressive industry regulations. Presently, I serve as VP of Patient Care Services with LifeBridge Health, Sinai Hospital.

Among my career achievements, I have collaboratively led multiple significant projects driven by leaders as the Board of Directors and Executive Committee level, including an initiative that realized \$20M in benefits for a safety net healthcare system.

Additionally, I am recognized as a healthcare industry expert and thought leader in change management, with a record of national and global lectures as well as multiple published research materials.

Specialties: Executive Leadership, Healthcare Management, Consulting, Operations Management, Profitability, P&L, Strategic Planning, Budget Planning, Communications, Change management.

Experience

LifeBridge Health
Vice President
June 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months)
Baltimore, Maryland Area

CNO

Navigant

Director

October 2012 - June 2018 (5 years 9 months)

Princeton, New Jersey

Lead 20-member teams within complex, multifaceted consultancy engagements. Coach and train team members. Focused on improving operational and clinical efficiencies, driving cost reductions and enhancing team performance. Build and launch cultural change programs.

- Managed year-long operational turnaround engagement for two-hospital system, achieving \$24M bottom-line savings through workforce and operational redesign. Key point of contact with executive team and Board of Trustees. Results also included improved patient access, quality and safety.
- Led province of Alberta to improve operational performance by enhancing patient throughput, access and clinical functions. Decreased LOS by one day and developed rapid assessment unit in ED within nationalized medicine model.

Price Waterhouse Coopers
Healthcare Advisory
February 2010 - November 2012 (2 years 10 months)

Drove transformational change through innovative methodologies, leadership and staff development, workload management and process redesign.

Handled end-to-end aspects of client account management included ongoing communications and documentation.

- Captured \$26M+ in savings by spearheading transformation of 1,500 bed safety-net system with transplant and trauma service lines. Identified and implemented productivity and workflow opportunities.
- Led implementation of Operational Resource and Clinical Management Program resulting in deep reduction in length of stay by .5 days in two months for multi-hospital system generating \$5.5M+ in value.

Healthcare Solutions Unlimited, LLC Principal

January 2009 - January 2010 (1 year 1 month)

Directed self-built healthcare and corporate consultancy. Oversaw client base with needs across crew resource management (CRM), microsystem thinking,

appreciative inquiry (AI), enabling technology assessment and demand and capacity matching.

- Subject matter expert in practice management, business administration, strategic planning, team performance, client service, budget administration and quality assurance.
- Developed and continuously refined change-focused portfolio.

Vistaar Healthcare Solutions Co-Founder, SVP Clinical Services November 2006 - January 2009 (2 years 3 months)

Executed COO functions for clinical consulting and technology services firm. Built teams across all clinical, ancillary and support services. Interfaced with customers, ensuring positive experiences and high rates of retention.

- Clients rated #1 in North America for patient flow and Milliman best practices for Length of Stay.
- Captured \$10M in annual savings by incorporating innovative technologies and process improvements.

Joint nomination with client for Joint Commission's John M. Eisenberg Award for Quality and Safety.

Overlook Hospital, Atlantic Health Systems Chief Nursing Officer | Interim Chief Operations Officer January 1999 - December 2006 (8 years) Summit, NJ

Interim COO over development of strategic 5-year plan and quality improvement initiatives. Thrived within 470-bed acute care facility.

Administered \$200M budget. Framed and presented insights to Board.

- Generated \$26M in savings in 9 months via leadership over Executive Committee of 1,500 bed safety-net system transformation.
- Steered implementation of Clinical Management Program including development of resource center that generated \$5.5M.
- Created and supported launch of breakthrough, technology-enabled solution providing real-time monitoring and metrics reporting functions.

- Project managed \$15M emergency department expansion, among multiple other construction initiatives.
- Attained \$1M in grant funding and national recognition in driving buildout of safety, patient education and customer satisfaction improvements.

Overlook Hospital

Operations Manager

January 1994 - January 1999 (5 years 1 month)

Responsible for operational and clinical management of Emergency Services.

Achieved national recognition through Emergency Department clinical and operational process improvement

Somerset Medical Center

7 years 1 month

Clinical Care Coordinator January 1992 - January 1994 (2 years 1 month)

Assistant Head Nurse January 1987 - January 1992 (5 years 1 month)

Education

Wharton/Johnson and Johnson Fellow

 \cdot (2004)

Seton Hall University

Master of Science, Advanced Practice Nurse Practitioner , Health Sciences Leadership \cdot (1980 - 1985)

Columbia University

Bachelor of Science, Nursing (1976)